Contact

samylee.baez@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/samylee-baez-michel-bba-bsn-rn-cmsrn-29327867 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Customer Satisfaction
Customer Service
Teamwork

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse (CMSRN)

New York State Registered Nurse

Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation /
Basic Life Support for the Healthcare
Provider

Honors-Awards

University Scholars Award
College Honors: Magna cum laude
Dean's List recipient - Spring-Fall
'13, Spring '16

Departmental Honors, Presidential Scholar

Upper Classman Recognition Award: Spring'15 - Fall'16

Samylee Baez-Michel, BBA, BSN, RN-CMSRN

Registered Nurse

Greater New York City Area

Summary

Bilingual/Bicultural second-degree Cum Laude baccalaureate, Board-Certified RN at NYP/CUIMC.

My experiences working with people have allowed me to acquire and develop excellent communication, social and interpersonal skills. Most importantly, these experiences have shifted my career goals into the wonderful field of Nursing, where I can serve a great purpose each and every day. My career allows me to provide compassionate, individualized nursing care for my patients and be more involved in the general welfare of people.

The ability to care for others and promote their health and well-being is substantially valuable for me. A career in Nursing allows me to help others and best meet their needs, providing direct patient care and support while offering a positive experience and striving to make a difference in people's lives.

LICENSURE

Licensed New York State Registered Nurse, March 2017

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Medical Surgical Registered Nurse (CMSRN), January 2020
- Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation/ Basic Life Support for the Healthcare Provider, November 2013

AFFILIATIONS

National Student Nurses Association (NSNA)
 Member

- National Association of Hispanic Nurses (NAHN)
 Member
- New York State Nurses Association (NYSNA)
 Member

Experience

New York-Presbyterian Hospital Registered Nurse August 2017 - Present (3 years) Greater New York City Area

Columbia New York Presbyterian Student Nurse September 2016 - December 2016 (4 months) Clinical Experience - Fall 2016

7HN Surgical Stepdown 36-bed unit

Work 1:1 with RN to provide individualized, direct patient care.

Nursing skills have been gained in tracheostomy care, suctioning,
maintenance of IV/PICC lines, medication administration (PO, SQ, IV / IVPB),
fluid boluses, tube feedings, IV and foley catheter care as well as removal.

Familiar with Omnicell automated healthcare system.

Provide care for patients with distinct needs, including VAD patients, tracheostomy, post-surgical, and vents.

Aid in prioritizing care and maintaining patient safety at all times.

Assist in the admissions process, discharge planning, bedside end of shift reports, medication administration and charting for clients under RN supervision and guidance (clinical preceptorship).

Clinical Experience - Spring 2016 Student Nurse at Maimonides Medical Center & New York Methodist Hospital January 2016 - May 2016 (5 months) Brooklyn, NY

Med-Surg; Pediatrics clinical rotations

- Conducted routine pre-op and post-op assessments (head-to-toe, vital signs)
- Assisted with ADLs and nursing interventions as per individualized plan of care

• Aided in the provision of patient care/ education, discharge instructions and medication administration under RN supervision and guidance.

Clinical Experience - Fall 2015

4 months

Student Nurse at Mt. Sinai -Beth Israel, Bernstein Pavilion September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months)

New York, NY

Behavioral Health

- Conducted mental status examinations
- Maintained therapeutic communication and developed nursing care plans to assist clients with promotion, maintenance and restoration of behavioral health.

Student Nurse at Queens Hospital Center September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months) Queens, NY

OB: Labor and Delivery; Postpartum

- Performed newborn assessments
- · Assisted with neonatal care
- Provided postpartum care
- Performed head-to-toe assessments, including BUBBLE-HE

Clinical Experience - Fall 2014

Student Nurse at Dr. Susan Smith McKinney Nursing & Rehabilitation Center

September 2014 - December 2014 (4 months)

594 Albany Ave, Brooklyn, NY 11203

Provided geriatric patient care, assisted with feedings, bathing

Gathered medical data, incl vital signs

Administered medications (oral and injection)

Reviewed patient care plans and MD orders

Long Island University Health & Medical Services Summer Intern June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

Julie 2014 - August 2014 (3 months

Brooklyn, NY

- Conducted outreach to incoming LIU freshman and transfer students to relay Immunization compliance requirements
- Participated in orientation sessions as Peer Evaluator

- Managed front desk including answering calls, as well as assisting with patient registrations and appointment scheduling
- Developed online database to monitor orientation outcomes using Microsoft Excel

University Health and Medical Services (UHMS)
Volunteer: Health & You Peer Educator (HYPE)
May 2013 - August 2013 (4 months)
175 Willoughby St. Brooklyn, NY. 11201

- * Provided orientation support for incoming new and transfer LIU students
- * Conducted health surveys
- * Focused on engagement of students and educating them on the importance of getting tested/routine health and wellness exams, nutrition and exercise

Allstate Insurance Agency Licensed Insurance Sales Representative January 2010 - March 2012 (2 years 3 months) Greater New York City Area

Assisted in planning and implementation of sales goals

Completed new business applications to improve company insurance sales, focusing on retention, cross-sell opportunities and minimizing loss ratio

Aided clients with claims filings, premium payments, policy inquiries and changes to retain business and improve customer satisfaction

LICENSES

• Property & Casualty Insurance License

Castle Financial Services
Head Teller
April 2007 - August 2009 (2 years 5 months)
Greater New York City Area

Assisted customers with check cashing, bill payments, Western Union money transfers, money orders, EBT transactions and Pre-paid Visa debit cards

Utilized CashWise Financial Software to manage cash transactions and maintain daily analysis reports

Supervised tellers and processed bank deliveries

United Garment Group Corporation

Secretary

September 2004 - April 2007 (2 years 8 months)

Maintained customer invoices and payment transactions using QuickBooks Financial Software

Processed invoices, entered data, kept records of financial affairs using Microsoft Excel

Conducted outreach to customers for individual orders, shipments and payments

SBCC Management Corporation
Office Assistant
May 2004 - September 2004 (5 months)
Seasonal

Filed confidential HUD paperwork for tenants

Utilized a multi-line system to respond to a high volume of tenant inquiries

Handled all other clerical duties, including database entries

Education

LIU Nursing Graduate

Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2013 - 2016)

Long Island University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN), RN · (2013 - 2016)

City University of New York-Herbert H. Lehman College Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA), Finance, Human Resources · (2005 - 2010)